Cameron Leach

949.422.4800 | cameron.leach@gmail.com

Profile

Software Applications Engineer with qualities of a strong leader and can communicate effectively with technical and non-technical team members. Currently manages backend platform engineering for consumer-facing websites disney.com and starwars.com, with a primary background in search and information retrieval. Has experience working on both small and large teams requiring the ability to stay organized and collaborative in fast-paced agile environments.

Experience

Disney Interactive

Glendale, CA

Manager, Software Engineering

Jan 2014-Present

- Leads product and engineering for backend content management and data platform, which powers Disney's flagship responsive websites disney.com and starwars.com
- Responsible for backend engineering effort in the relaunch of starwars.com under the Disney banner for the first time
- Provides architectural and technical guidance on site-serving APIs and producer interface applications built with Ruby on Rails backed by MongoDB
- Managed revision of recommendation engine for Disney video portal that suggests related content through machine learning using Hadoop

Staff Software Engineer

Jan 2013-Dec 2013

- · Led front end and search engineering teams responsible for newly relaunched disney.com
- Migrated several legacy disney.com sites and portals onto search platform, including Disney Channel, Disney XD and Walt Disney Company corporate sites
- Launched internationalized front end sites and search platforms in Latin America and Europe, supporting multiple languages in a cohesive and integrated ecosystem

Senior Software Engineer

May 2011-Dec 2012

- Architected and built an entirely new search platform for the major relaunch of disney.com using open-source software and frameworks like Apache Solr and Spring
- Optimized primary search algorithm leading to an increase in direct affiliate revenue from search on disney.com over 500% year over year
- Search platform includes multiple scalable indices supporting varied clients through a common API including a producer-facing content management system backend as well as other frontfacing sites like disneybaby.com
- Spearheaded automation through continuous integration with Jenkins and Capistrano for scripted deployments
- Worked on a fast-paced agile Labs team whose purpose was to innovate on experimental features, many of which became the foundation for the new disney.com

CityGrid Media/Citysearch

West Hollywood, CA

Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2008-Apr 2011

- Led team of search engineers in deployment of new search functionality during major site redesign with algorithm improvements leading to increases in conversions and revenue of over \$500k per year
- Architected and scaled multiple clusters of Apache Solr-based indexes containing more than
 18 million unique business listings performing advanced geo-spatial local searches

- Responsible for development and deployment of CityGrid public content APIs serving localized business listing profiles, search, deals and user reviews used by more than 100 partners and developers
- Principal engineer on cross-functional scrum team responsible for building RESTful web applications for submission of user generated content including images, reviews and tweets from Twitter
- Built server-side component of auto complete/predictive text functionality using Apache Lucene with index containing over 3 million search terms localized to specific geographic regions
- Built self-enrollment wizard using Spring Webflow for backend customer system for new potential merchant signups

Warner Bros. Advanced Digital Services

Burbank, CA

Associate Application Engineer

May 2006-Apr 2008

- Led development of online video distribution applications for both client and server utilizing
 Java technologies and Windows DRM to generate cost savings of over \$1 million for studio
- Involved in development of several consumer facing Java applications including main portal,
 CRM application, and content management systems

Walt Disney TV Animation/DisneyToon Studios

Burbank, CA

Undergraduate Associate

Jun 2005-Aug 2005

- · Improved software scripts, increasing efficiency of the animation production pipeline
- Provided assistance in production archival, system administration and technology upkeep

Education

University of Southern California

Los Angeles, CA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering and Computer Science

December 2005

- Graduated Magna Cum Laude
- · USC Presidential Scholar
- · USC SCion Scholar

Skills

Java (EE, SE) SQL

Amaraha Calu

Ruby Apache Solr

Lucene XML

Spring Framework HTML

Hibernate Maven JavaScript

Ruby on Rails Web Services/APIs CSS

Sinatra REST

Mac OS X

Apache Tomcat

MongoDB Continuous Integration Unix/Linux